JAMES McGLONE

Perth, Western Australia 6017
Phone: 0421 44 22 36 | Email: jamespmcglone@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jamespmcglone/

Github: https://github.com/jpmc3630/ | Portfolio: https://github.com/jpmc3630/ | Portfolio: https://jpmc3630.github.io/ | StackOverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/12001877/james-mcglone/

SUMMARY

Passionate web developer who returned to mature age study with the goal of turning a lifelong hobby into a successful career. Recently brushed up on the latest web technology trends and current industry standards as a graduate of UWA's Full-Stack Developer Bootcamp Certificate.

Recognised as a proactive, creative, and resourceful problem solver. Enjoys designing aesthetically rich user interfaces, and the user-experience focus of front-end development, but also the technical problem solving challenges of back-end development. Ultimately loves bringing these two aspects together to deliver smooth, full-stack apps that exceed expectations.

Believes in the importance of strong interpersonal skills in this technical field. Strong communicator, works well in a team, known to motivate teammates and keep projects on track.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Deliverables: Web Design, Single Page / Progessive Web App Development, UX/UI, Frontend and Backend Development, Database Development, API Development, Git Version Control.

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript / jQuery.

Frontend: ReactJS, Ionic, Bootstrap.

Backend: NodeJS, ExpressJS, JSON, RESTful APIs.

Database: MySQL / Sequelize, MongoDB / Mongoose, Google Firebase. **Other Libraries/APIs:** MapBox, Doteny, Axios, WebMidi, WebRTC, SocketIO.

Deployment: Git, Sourcetree, Github, Heroku, Netlify.

Project Management: Github Projects, Agile, Kanban, Scrum. **Hardware Coding:** Arduino C/C++, Hardware interface design.

Other Software: MS Office Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro,

Ableton Live, Audacity, QLC+.

PROJECTS

Synths - Share Analog Audio Hardware Online

Deployed: https://synths.herokuapp.com Github: https://github.com/jpmc3630/synths

- A web app that interfaces with physical hardware. Primarily designed to allow users to
 host hardware audio synthesisers online, and allow other users to remotely connect and
 use the hardware synths to design sounds in real time. Users can save sound design
 'patches' to their accounts.
- Built in React and served with Node/Express. Audio and video streams use WebRTC, synth control data uses SocketIO & WebMidi API. Javascript, CSS, HTML.

Let's Go - Collaborative Travel Itinerary Web App

Deployed: https://jpmc3630.github.io/letsgo/ Github: https://github.com/jpmc3630/letsgo

- This web app allows holidays to be planned and plotted on a map. Trips can be shared with friends, and multiple people can work on the same travel itinerary in real-time. It was designed to allow everyone to get involved and excited about the future trip.
- MapBox API, Google Firebase, Javascript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Ionic, RESTful APIs.

Midi-Hero - Web Browser Game

Deployed: https://midi-hero.herokuapp.com/ Github: https://github.com/jpmc3630/midi-hero/

- Similar to Guitar Hero, this full-stack game creates levels by analysing MIDI files, and lets players attempt to break high scores by playing the drums along to visual cues and background music.
- MIDI files, web-audio-tinysynth JS library, Node, Express, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Express-Handlebars, MySQL, Sequelize, AJAX.

EXPERIENCE

Audio/Lighting Technician 360 Artist Logistics

2018-Present

Perth, WA

Setting up audio, lighting, and digital screens for large scale events & concerts.

Lighting Designer & Technician Dark Matter Executions

2017-Present

Perth. WA

Custom event lighting design, virtual 3D modelling, client consultation, installation and operation at events & concerts.

Key Accomplishments:

Major stage lighting design & operation, Blossom Festival 2019

Document Courier Panther Corp

2016-Present

Perth, WA

Owner/driver delivering company documents to clients in Perth Metro area.

Owner/Manager Amplified Commercial Cleaning

2010 – 2016

Melbourne, VIC

Operating a contract cleaning business servicing Melbourne's hospitality industry. Building rapport with clients and subcontractors, implementing and reviewing systems, supervising and training subcontractors, managing accounts, sales and marketing.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Developer Bootcamp Certificate: University of Western Australia, Perth, WA

Bachelor of Arts, Media and Information (Film and Television): Curtin University, Perth, WA

Graduated High School: Churchlands Senior High School, Perth, WA